prochoiceamerica.org 2012-12-16

# NARAL Pro-Choice America's Privacy Policy :: NARAL Pro-Choice America

At NARAL Pro-Choice America, the NARAL Pro-Choice America Foundation and NARAL Pro-Choice America PAC, we are committed to protecting your privacy online. Our privacy policy explains the information practices NARAL Pro-Choice America uses related to: 

  * How we use your information 
  * How we protect your information 
  * How to unsubscribe from mailing lists 
  * How to correct information you provided 
  * How to contact us about privacy

NARAL Pro-Choice America has also signed the Direct Marketing Associations (DMA) Privacy Promise to American Consumers that took effect for all DMA members on July 1, 1999. This policy can be found at [www.the-dma.org](http://www.the-dma.org/).

Our site links to a limited number of other web sites. NARAL Pro-Choice America, the NARAL Pro-Choice America Foundation and NARAL Pro-Choice America PAC are not responsible for the content or the privacy policies of these web sites.

### How Do We Use the Information You Provide NARAL Pro-Choice America, NARAL Pro-Choice America Foundation, and NARAL Pro-Choice America PAC?

**When you volunteer online or sign up for the Choice Action Network:** Our forms ask you to give NARAL Pro-Choice America, the NARAL Pro-Choice America Foundation and NARAL Pro-Choice America PAC contact information including: name, mailing address, e-mail address and how you wish to help us. Unless you opt out, we will use your e-mail address to send you updates on reproductive health issues and to ask you to take an action such as contacting your Congressperson. Additionally, you may receive periodic fundraising communications.

NARAL Pro-Choice America, the NARAL Pro-Choice America Foundation and NARAL Pro-Choice America PAC exchange e-mail names within its sister organizations to the extent permitted by law but not with other non-NARAL Pro-Choice America organizations. You may remove your name from our e-mailing lists at any time by emailing a request to [can@ProChoiceAmerica.org](mailto:can@ProChoiceAmerica.org).

We use your address information to send you information about NARAL Pro-Choice America, the NARAL Pro-Choice America Foundation and NARAL Pro-Choice America PAC and to help match your interests to our grassroots organizing efforts. Since we are a grassroots organization, we will provide your contact information to our national field staff and State Affiliates. You may remove your name from all of our volunteer and activist lists by sending your request to [can@ProChoiceAmerica.org](mailto:can@ProChoiceAmerica.org). We do not share our volunteer or activist lists with any other site or any other non-NARAL Pro-Choice America entity.

 **When you contribute money online:** NARAL Pro-Choice America and the NARAL Pro-Choice America Foundation accept contributions by credit card online. In addition to your name, mailing address and email address, we make a note of your telephone number if you choose to provide it, but you are not required to do so. By providing us with this information, you allow us to quickly contact you concerning federal legislation, our grassroots efforts and new publications such as our _Who Decides? The Status of Women's Reproductive Rights in the United States_.

NARAL Pro-Choice America may exchange or rent our contributor list of names and mailing addresses to other organizations unless you use the opt-out feature on the contribution page. We do not exchange e-mail addresses.

Unless you opt out, we may use the information you provide us when you contribute by mail or online, or when you download a form from our web site to contact you for other purposes or to solicit you for additional contributions.

NARAL Pro-Choice America purchases mailing lists from other organizations and as a result you may receive mailings or e-mail from us.

**When you sign up to receive text messages on your cell phone through Txt4Choice** : You may sign up to receive text messages on your cell phone from NARAL Pro-Choice America, the NARAL Pro-Choice America Foundation, and NARAL Pro-Choice America PAC by completing a form on our website, opting in through some other online transaction, or texting a keyword to our shortcode. NARAL Pro-Choice America, the NARAL Pro-Choice America Foundation, and NARAL Pro-Choice America PAC permit its state-based network of affiliates to send text messages to text message subscribers. 

Unless you opt out, you will receive text messages regarding reproductive-choice related issues, often with ways to take action. You may remove your name from our text message subscription at any time by texting “stop” to 49609. 

Cell phone numbers provided for text messaging will only be used to send text messages. Unless you provide your cell phone number through another mechanism, such as by completing an online transaction, we will not call your cell phone number. Cell phone numbers will not be traded or exchanged with any outside organization.

If you include an email address in a text message reply, you are opting in to receive email alerts through the Choice Action Network. After you send an email in reply to a text message, you will receive a confirmation email with information about how to unsubscribe. 

**Cookies:** A cookie is a tiny text file that is stored on your computer when you visit a web site such as NARAL Pro-Choice America's. To enhance your experience with our site, some pages may use cookies. Additionally, portions of our site link to external sites—such as GetActive and Yahoo!—that have their own Privacy Policy governing the use of cookies.  Please refer to these external sites for additional information.

ProChoiceAmerica.org will use cookies to tailor your experience on our site to your general geographic location and interests. In these cases, we will always ask permission before placing a cookie file on your computer, and unless you choose to furnish us with personally identifiable information there will be nothing in our cookie files that identifies you personally. Should you choose to furnish the site with personally identifiable information, this information may be linked to the data stored in the cookie.

 **Information on children:** NARAL Pro-Choice America, the NARAL Pro-Choice America Foundation and NARAL Pro-Choice America PAC do not specifically ask children under 18 for any information and do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information about them.

### How Do We Protect Your Information?

Our web site has security measures in place to protect against the loss, misuse or alteration of the information under our control. Our server is located in a locked, secure environment. All databases containing personal information are securely stored on a separate system that is not connected to the Internet.

When you contribute online, we use a secure server and encryption to protect your credit card number and other personal information during transmission.

### Unsubscribing from Email

All messages sent by NARAL Pro-Choice America's Choice Action Network and other e-lists include information on how to unsubscribe quickly and easily through an automated system.

If, at any time, you wish to opt-out of receiving communications from us, you may also send a written request to the Choice Action Network. Our unsubscribe requests are processed every week. If you wish to unsubscribe or need to process a change to your email address, send your requested changes to [can@ProChoiceAmerica.org](mailto:can@ProChoiceAmerica.org).

### Correcting Your Information

NARAL Pro-Choice America's web site does not require you to register nor do we assign visitors a password, except in Members Only sections. Therefore, we have no way to verify your identity when you visit our site. To protect your privacy, we provide a password protected form to update your information online. If you need to correct or update your information, please send e-mail to [membership@ProChoiceAmerica.org](mailto:membership@ProChoiceAmerica.org) and we will give you instructions on how to use our secure online member update form.

Contacting us about privacy

If you have any questions about our privacy policy, the information we have collected from you online, the practices of this site or your interaction with this web site, send us an e-mail. If you have made a donation, please contact [membership@ProChoiceAmerica.org](mailto:membership@ProChoiceAmerica.org). If you are a member of the Choice Action Network, please contact [CAN@ProChoiceAmerica.org](mailto:CAN@ProChoiceAmerica.org). 

You can also reach us via US Mail at:

 **Privacy  
NARAL Pro-Choice America - Membership Department**  
1156 15th Street, NW  
Suite 700  
Washington, DC 20005

**Privacy  
NARAL Pro-Choice America – Choice Action Network   
**1156 15th Street, NW  
Suite 700  
Washington, DC 20005
